<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>persian cookbook &#8211; Persian Cookbook</title>
	<atom:link href="https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/tag/persian-cookbook/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com</link>
	<description>A collection of Persian cookbooks</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:05:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">197439166</site>	<item>
		<title>From the Land of Nightingales and Roses: Recipes from the Persian Kitchen</title>
		<link>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/from-the-land-of-nightingales-and-roses-recipes-from-the-persian-kitchen/</link>
					<comments>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/from-the-land-of-nightingales-and-roses-recipes-from-the-persian-kitchen/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[persiancookbook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 17:25:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Maryam Sinaiee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persian cookbook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/?p=120</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In From the Land of Nightingales and Roses, Iranian food blogger and home cook, Maryam Sinaiee, takes us through a full year in the Persian kitchen. Each seasonal chapter offers up delicious recipes alongside insights into the festivals, traditions and rituals that color day-to-day life in this region. From spring through to winter, Maryam offers... <div class="link-more"><a href="https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/from-the-land-of-nightingales-and-roses-recipes-from-the-persian-kitchen/">Read More</a></div>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>In From the Land of Nightingales and Roses, Iranian food blogger and home cook, Maryam Sinaiee, takes us through a full year in the Persian kitchen. Each seasonal chapter offers up delicious recipes alongside insights into the festivals, traditions and rituals that color day-to-day life in this region. From spring through to winter, Maryam offers the reader a true taste of real Persian cookingLamb and Eggplant Stew, Baked Fish with Tamarind, and Rosewater Ice Cream with Pistachios. Full of flavor, history and culture, Maryams recipes are a wonderful introduction to the varied and delectable cuisine of this region. Colorful, stunning photography evoking the vibrancy and romance of the country will bring Iran into your home and make you fall in love with this unique way to cook and enjoy food.</p></blockquote>



<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link" href="https://amzn.to/2SwdWBN">Buy Now on Amazon for <img src="https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=persiancookbook-20&l=alb&o=1&a=1623719674" width="1px" height="1px" alt="" style="position: fixed !important; bottom: -1px !important; right: -1px !important; border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /></a></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/from-the-land-of-nightingales-and-roses-recipes-from-the-persian-kitchen/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">120</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bottom of the Pot: Persian Recipes and Stories</title>
		<link>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/bottom-of-the-pot-persian-recipes-and-stories/</link>
					<comments>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/bottom-of-the-pot-persian-recipes-and-stories/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[persiancookbook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 16:54:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Naz Deravian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persian cookbook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/?p=75</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Naz Deravian lays out the multi-hued canvas of a Persian meal, with 100+ recipes adapted to an American home kitchen and interspersed with Naz&#8217;s celebrated essays exploring the idea of home.At eight years old, Naz Deravian left Iran with her family during the height of the 1979 Iranian Revolution and hostage crisis. Over the following... <div class="link-more"><a href="https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/bottom-of-the-pot-persian-recipes-and-stories/">Read More</a></div>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>Naz Deravian lays out the multi-hued canvas of a Persian meal, with 100+ recipes adapted to an American home kitchen and interspersed with Naz&#8217;s celebrated essays exploring the idea of home.<br>At eight years old, Naz Deravian left Iran with her family during the height of the 1979 Iranian Revolution and hostage crisis. Over the following ten years, they emigrated from Iran to Rome to Vancouver, carrying with them books of Persian poetry, tiny jars of saffron threads, and always, the knowledge that home can be found in a simple, perfect pot of rice. As they traverse the world in search of a place to land, Naz&#8217;s family finds comfort and familiarity in pots of hearty aash, steaming pomegranate and walnut chicken, and of course, tahdig: the crispy, golden jewels of rice that form a crust at the bottom of the pot. The best part, saved for last.&nbsp;<br>In&nbsp;<em>Bottom of the Pot</em>, Naz, now an award-winning writer and passionate home cook based in LA, opens up to us a world of fragrant rose petals and tart dried limes, music and poetry, and the bittersweet twin pulls of assimilation and nostalgia. In over 100 recipes, Naz introduces us to Persian food made from a global perspective, at home in an American kitchen.</p></blockquote>



<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Bottom-Pot-Persian-Recipes-Stories/dp/1250134412/ref=as_li_ss_tl?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1546278841&amp;sr=1-4&amp;keywords=persian+cookbooks&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=persiancookbook-20&amp;linkId=3c96130f2b8ee913456dc0a0e95fbb8d&amp;language=en_US">Buy Now on Amazon for <img src="https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=persiancookbook-20&l=alb&o=1&a=1250134412" width="1px" height="1px" alt="" style="position: fixed !important; bottom: -1px !important; right: -1px !important; border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /></a></div>



<div class="wp-block-columns has-2-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="http://bottomofthepot.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/36660485_1715092758544628_1758889545522216960_n.jpg" alt=""/><figcaption>Photo credit Jonathan Vandiveer</figcaption></figure>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>NAZ DERAVIAN is a writer and actor born in Iran. She grew up in Italy and Canada and now lives in Los Angeles with her husband and two children. She is the award-winning voice behind the food blog&nbsp;<em>Bottom of the Pot</em>, which won the 2015 International Association of Culinary Professionals (IACP) Award for best narrative culinary blog. She has also been twice nominated is several categories for the&nbsp;<em>Saveur</em>Food Blog Awards.</p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/bottom-of-the-pot-persian-recipes-and-stories/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">75</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pomegranates and Roses: My Persian Family Recipes</title>
		<link>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/pomegranates-and-roses-my-persian-family-recipes/</link>
					<comments>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/pomegranates-and-roses-my-persian-family-recipes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[persiancookbook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 17:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ariana Bundy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persian cookbook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/?p=107</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With stunning recipes and exquisite photography, Pomegranates and Roses captures the vibrant essence of Persian cuisine. Ariana Bundy, award-winning TV chef and presenter of the NatGeo People series &#8216;Ariana&#8217;s Persian Kitchen&#8217;, uses accessible ingredients to create sumptuous dishes. Ariana writes poignantly of the traditions cherished by her forefathers, when family mattered above all else and... <div class="link-more"><a href="https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/pomegranates-and-roses-my-persian-family-recipes/">Read More</a></div>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>With stunning recipes and exquisite photography, Pomegranates and Roses captures the vibrant essence of Persian cuisine. Ariana Bundy, award-winning TV chef and presenter of the NatGeo People series &#8216;Ariana&#8217;s Persian Kitchen&#8217;, uses accessible ingredients to create sumptuous dishes. Ariana writes poignantly of the traditions cherished by her forefathers, when family mattered above all else and sharing delicious food brought people together. Beautifully presented dishes, photographed by Lisa Linder are complemented by enchanting family stories that transport you to a forgotten land and time.</p></blockquote>



<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link" href="https://amzn.to/2BP8ove">Buy Now on Amazon for <img src="https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=persiancookbook-20&l=alb&o=1&a=1999982002" width="1px" height="1px" alt="" style="position: fixed !important; bottom: -1px !important; right: -1px !important; border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /></a></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/pomegranates-and-roses-my-persian-family-recipes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">107</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Persian Cookbook: The Manual</title>
		<link>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/a-persian-cookbook-the-manual/</link>
					<comments>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/a-persian-cookbook-the-manual/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[persiancookbook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 18:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Saman Hassibi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persian cookbook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/?p=158</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This book brings pieces of the oldest Persian cooking manuscripts into its first English translation, vital for culinary enthusiasts worldwide. Food has always acted as a focal point around which people of different origins come together. Food has also been one of the best elements to introduce different cultures. Today, perhaps more than ever, people... <div class="link-more"><a href="https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/a-persian-cookbook-the-manual/">Read More</a></div>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>This book brings pieces of the oldest Persian cooking manuscripts into its first English translation, vital for culinary enthusiasts worldwide. Food has always acted as a focal point around which people of different origins come together. Food has also been one of the best elements to introduce different cultures. Today, perhaps more than ever, people in the West need understand Middle Eastern culture. Perhaps, this book on the culture and lives of people in Middle East can paint a different picture to what been published before.</p></blockquote>



<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Persian-Cookbook-Manual-Saman-Hassibi/dp/1909248592/ref=as_li_ss_tl?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1546282568&amp;sr=1-3&amp;keywords=persian+cookbooks+best+sellers&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=persiancookbook-20&amp;linkId=3caa96e8de700c0161daf8a14a7577bf&amp;language=en_US">Buy Now on Amazon for <img src="https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=persiancookbook-20&l=alb&o=1&a=1909248592" width="1px" height="1px" alt="" style="position: fixed !important; bottom: -1px !important; right: -1px !important; border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /></a></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/a-persian-cookbook-the-manual/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">158</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Enchantingly Easy Persian Cookbook: 100 Simple Recipes for Beloved Persian Food Favorites</title>
		<link>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/the-enchantingly-easy-persian-cookbook-100-simple-recipes-for-beloved-persian-food-favorites/</link>
					<comments>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/the-enchantingly-easy-persian-cookbook-100-simple-recipes-for-beloved-persian-food-favorites/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[persiancookbook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 18:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Shadi HasanzadeNemati]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persian cookbook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/?p=94</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[From the kitchens of Persian families to your dining table, with&#160;The Enchantingly Easy Persian Cookbook&#160;you’ll enjoy easy-to-follow recipes that achieve the vibrant flavors of authentic Persian cuisine.Yogurt, eggplant, lamb kebabs, saffron rice―if you have ever dined in a Persian restaurant then you know how rich, tantalizing, and satisfying Persian cuisine is. Yet many assume that... <div class="link-more"><a href="https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/the-enchantingly-easy-persian-cookbook-100-simple-recipes-for-beloved-persian-food-favorites/">Read More</a></div>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><strong>From the kitchens of Persian families to your dining table, with&nbsp;<em>The Enchantingly Easy Persian Cookbook</em>&nbsp;you’ll enjoy easy-to-follow recipes that achieve the vibrant flavors of authentic Persian cuisine.</strong><br>Yogurt, eggplant, lamb kebabs, saffron rice―if you have ever dined in a Persian restaurant then you know how rich, tantalizing, and satisfying Persian cuisine is. Yet many assume that making favorites, like Pomegranate and Walnut Stew or Saffron Syrup Cake, is too difficult to do at home.<br>Shadi HasanzadeNemati grew up in the kitchen of her Persian mother and can still remember being mesmerized by the sweet aromas of saffron and cinnamon. Inspired by her family’s heirloom recipes, Shadi has created a collection of simple, straightforward takes on authentic Persian favorites that are accessible enough for beginners, yet still fun for more seasoned cooks.<br><em>The Enchantingly Easy Persian Cookbook</em>&nbsp;brings the savory comforts and mystical essence of Persian home cooking to your dining table. The step-by-step instructions in this Persian cookbook make it easier than ever to create classic Persian mainstays in your own home.<br>In this uniquely simple Persian cookbook, you’ll find:<br>100 recipes specifically designed to make Persian cooking fun and stress-free for beginners<br><br>A handy how-to guide for preparing basic Persian ingredients―such as de-seeding pomegranates, making saffron-water, drying limes, and storing fresh herbs<br><br>Practical grocery shopping recommendations for Persian pantry staples like cardamom and sumac, plus useful photos for identifying unique ingredients such as ghee and clotted cream<br><br>Helpful labels that indicate each recipe’s level of difficulty, plus “worth the wait” labels for dishes that require more time<br><br>Tried-and-true tips and tricks to make Persian cooking easier and more successful<br><br>Memory sidebars that accompany especially treasured recipes, describing Shadi’s most cherished recollection connected to that dish<br>With the ease and simplicity of&nbsp;<em>The Enchantingly Easy Persian Cookbook</em>&nbsp;you’ll have more fun (and less stress) as you find the magic in new Persian fare, and rediscover the enchantment of recipes you already love.</p></blockquote>



<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link" href="https://amzn.to/2LI1Sei">Buy Now on Amazon for <img src="https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=persiancookbook-20&l=alb&o=1&a=1623157633" width="1px" height="1px" alt="" style="position: fixed !important; bottom: -1px !important; right: -1px !important; border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /></a></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/the-enchantingly-easy-persian-cookbook-100-simple-recipes-for-beloved-persian-food-favorites/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">94</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Saffron Tales: Recipes from the Persian Kitchen</title>
		<link>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/the-saffron-tales-recipes-from-the-persian-kitchen/</link>
					<comments>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/the-saffron-tales-recipes-from-the-persian-kitchen/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[persiancookbook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 17:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Yasmin Khan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persian cookbook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/?p=82</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Winner of the M.F.K Fisher Award for Excellence in Culinary Writing from Les Dames d&#8217;EscoffierNew York Times Best Cookbooks of the YearWall Street Journal&#160;Best Cookbooks of the YearBBC Food Programme&#160;Best Cookbooks of the Year A glorious celebration of the food and people of Iran, featuring stories from home kitchens and more than 80 delicious, modern... <div class="link-more"><a href="https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/the-saffron-tales-recipes-from-the-persian-kitchen/">Read More</a></div>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><strong>Winner of the M.F.K Fisher Award for Excellence in Culinary Writing from Les Dames d&#8217;Escoffier</strong><br><strong>New York Times Best Cookbooks of the Year</strong><br><strong>Wall Street Journal&nbsp;Best Cookbooks of the Year</strong><br><strong>BBC Food Programme&nbsp;Best Cookbooks of the Year</strong><br><br><strong>A glorious celebration of the food and people of Iran, featuring stories from home kitchens and more than 80 delicious, modern recipes.</strong><br><br><strong>&#8220;This is so much more than a compilation of recipes, gorgeous though they themselves are. This is a book that tells a story, both cultural and personal, and her voice is as engaging as her food.&#8221;&nbsp;&#8211;Nigella Lawson</strong><br><br><strong>&#8220;Barberries,&nbsp;fresh herbs,&nbsp;date molasses, dried limes, saffron; Yasmin&#8217;s Persian pantry staples are a roll call of my favourite ingredients. Her recipes are a mouthwatering showcase of a beautiful country.&#8221; &#8211;Yotam Ottolenghi</strong><br><strong>&#8220;Not just a great cookbook but a book full of stories – a love letter to Iran and its people.&#8221; &#8211;Diana Henry</strong><br>Armed with little more than a notebook and a bottle of pomegranate molasses, and fueled by memories of her family&#8217;s farm in the lush seaside province of Gilan, British-Iranian cook Yasmin Khan traversed Iran in search of the most delicious recipes for this Persian cookbook.&nbsp;<br>Her quest took her from the snowy mountains of Tabriz to the cosmopolitan cafés of Tehran and the pomegranate orchards of Isfahan, where she was welcomed into the homes of artists, farmers, electricians, and teachers. Through her travels, she gained a unique insight into the culinary secrets of the Persian kitchen, and the lives of ordinary Iranians today.&nbsp;<br>In&nbsp;<em>The Saffron Tales</em>, Yasmin weaves together a tapestry of stories from Iranian home kitchens with exclusive photography and fragrant, modern recipes that are rooted in the rich tradition of Persian cooking. All fully accessible for the home cook, Yasmin&#8217;s recipes range from the inimitable fesenjoon (chicken with walnuts and pomegranates) to kofte berenji (lamb meatballs stuffed with prunes and barberries) and ghalyieh maygoo (shrimp, coriander, and tamarind stew). She also offers a wealth of vegetarian dishes, including tahcheen (baked saffron and eggplant rice) and domaj (mixed herb, flatbread, and feta salad), as well as sumptuous desserts such as rose and almond cake, and sour cherry and dark chocolate cookies.&nbsp;<br>With stunning photography from all corners of Iran and gorgeous recipe images, this lavish cookbook rejoices in the land, life, flavors, and food of an enigmatic and beautiful country.</p></blockquote>



<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Saffron-Tales-Recipes-Persian-Kitchen/dp/1632867109/ref=as_li_ss_tl?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1546278841&amp;sr=1-6&amp;keywords=persian+cookbooks&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=persiancookbook-20&amp;linkId=25924155ba58bd28c81bc17ff2c1b00e&amp;language=en_US">Buy Now on Amazon for <img src="https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=persiancookbook-20&l=alb&o=1&a=1632867109" width="1px" height="1px" alt="" style="position: fixed !important; bottom: -1px !important; right: -1px !important; border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /></a></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/the-saffron-tales-recipes-from-the-persian-kitchen/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">82</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Taste of Persia: A Cook&#8217;s Travels Through Armenia, Azerbaijan, Georgia, Iran, and Kurdistan</title>
		<link>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/taste-of-persia-a-cooks-travels-through-armenia-azerbaijan-georgia-iran-and-kurdistan/</link>
					<comments>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/taste-of-persia-a-cooks-travels-through-armenia-azerbaijan-georgia-iran-and-kurdistan/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[persiancookbook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 17:11:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Naomi Duguid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persian cookbook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/?p=97</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Winner, James Beard Award for Best Book of the Year, International (2017)Winner, IACP Award for Best Cookbook of the Year in Culinary Travel (2017) Named a Best Cookbook of the Year by&#160;The Boston Globe,&#160;Food &#38; Wine,&#160;The Los Angeles Times,&#160;The New York Times,&#160;The New York Times Book Review,&#160;The San Francisco Chronicle,&#160;USA Today, and&#160;The Wall Street Journal... <div class="link-more"><a href="https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/taste-of-persia-a-cooks-travels-through-armenia-azerbaijan-georgia-iran-and-kurdistan/">Read More</a></div>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><strong>Winner, James Beard Award for Best Book of the Year, International (2017)<br>Winner, IACP Award for Best Cookbook of the Year in Culinary Travel (2017)<br><br>Named a Best Cookbook of the Year by&nbsp;<em>The Boston Globe</em>,&nbsp;<em>Food &amp; Wine</em>,&nbsp;<em>The Los Angeles Times</em>,&nbsp;<em>The New York Times</em>,&nbsp;<em>The New York Times Book Review</em>,&nbsp;<em>The San Francisco Chronicle</em>,&nbsp;<em>USA Today</em>, and&nbsp;<em>The Wall Street Journal</em><br><br>“A reason to celebrate . . . a fascinating culinary excursion.”&nbsp;<em>—The New York Times</em></strong><br><br>Though the countries in the Persian culinary region are home to diverse religions, cultures, languages, and politics, they are linked by beguiling food traditions and a love for the fresh and the tart. Color and spark come from ripe red pomegranates, golden saffron threads, and the fresh herbs served at every meal. Grilled kebabs, barbari breads, pilafs, and brightly colored condiments are everyday fare, as are rich soup-stews called ash and alluring sweets like rose water pudding and date-nut halvah.<br><br>Our ambassador to this tasty world is the incomparable Naomi Duguid, who for more than 20 years has been bringing us exceptional recipes and mesmerizing tales from regions seemingly beyond our reach. More than 125 recipes, framed with stories and photographs of people and places, introduce us to a culinary paradise where ancient legends and ruins rub shoulders with new beginnings—where a wealth of history and culinary traditions makes it a compelling place to read about for cooks and travelers and for anyone hankering to experience the food of a wider world.</p></blockquote>



<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link" href="https://amzn.to/2SpvjEh">Buy Now on Amazon for <img src="https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=persiancookbook-20&l=alb&o=1&a=1579655483" width="1px" height="1px" alt="" style="position: fixed !important; bottom: -1px !important; right: -1px !important; border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /></a></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/taste-of-persia-a-cooks-travels-through-armenia-azerbaijan-georgia-iran-and-kurdistan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">97</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Jewelled Kitchen: A Stunning Collection of Lebanese, Moroccan, and Persian Recipes</title>
		<link>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/the-jewelled-kitchen-a-stunning-collection-of-lebanese-moroccan-and-persian-recipes/</link>
					<comments>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/the-jewelled-kitchen-a-stunning-collection-of-lebanese-moroccan-and-persian-recipes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[persiancookbook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 18:13:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bethany Kehdy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persian cookbook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/?p=164</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kehdy&#8217;s cookbook is an inspired collection of classics and innovative dishes from a part of the world which, at the moment, is enjoying its overdue place in the sun. Her contribution and original, thoughtful and delicious. Go get it! &#8211;Yottam Ottolenghi Bethany Kehdy is renowned for the contemporary Middle Eastern and North African recipes that she... <div class="link-more"><a href="https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/the-jewelled-kitchen-a-stunning-collection-of-lebanese-moroccan-and-persian-recipes/">Read More</a></div>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><em><strong>Kehdy&#8217;s cookbook is an inspired collection of classics and innovative dishes from a part of the world which, at the moment, is enjoying its overdue place in the sun. Her contribution and original, thoughtful and delicious. Go get it! &#8211;Yottam Ottolenghi</strong></em> Bethany Kehdy is renowned for the contemporary Middle Eastern and North African recipes that she publishes on her blog (dirtykitchensecrets.com). A Lebanese-American born in Houston, Texas and brought up in Lebanon, she spent countless hours learning to cook with her perfectionist <em>teta</em> (grandmother), her vivacious dad and her spirited aunts. Her recipes are a harmonious balance of classic and contemporary, as she draws upon her childhood roots while adding her own personal twist to these iconic recipes.<br><br>The cuisines from the Middle East and North Africa share many diverse influences and gorgeous key ingredients and spices, such as pomegranates, figs, pine nuts, saffron and sumac. Passionate about food and her heritage, this former Miss Lebanon showcases the sheer brilliance of the dishes of the Levant. Try a fragrant Fish Tagine with Preserved Lemons from the Moroccan chapter; fiery Lamb Shanks with Butterbeans and Tomatoes from the Lebanese; or delicately spiced Chicken, Walnuts and Pomegranate Stew from the Persian. All the cuisines of the regions are covered, including Egyptian, Palestinian, Syrian, Turkish, Iraqi and Jordanian, and all the recipes are easy to make. You&#8217;ll find yourself drawn into a whole new world and a whole new way of cooking.</p></blockquote>



<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Jewelled-Kitchen-Stunning-Collection-Lebanese/dp/1848992890/ref=as_li_ss_tl?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1546282568&amp;sr=1-9&amp;keywords=persian+cookbooks+best+sellers&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=persiancookbook-20&amp;linkId=da94ac7a49495d6d7856d95fb92b34d1&amp;language=en_US">Buy Now on Amazon for <img src="https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=persiancookbook-20&l=alb&o=1&a=1848992890" width="1px" height="1px" alt="" style="position: fixed !important; bottom: -1px !important; right: -1px !important; border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /></a></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/the-jewelled-kitchen-a-stunning-collection-of-lebanese-moroccan-and-persian-recipes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">164</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joon: Persian Cooking Made Simple</title>
		<link>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/joon-persian-cooking-made-simple/</link>
					<comments>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/joon-persian-cooking-made-simple/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[persiancookbook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 16:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Najmieh Batmanglij]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persian cookbook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/?p=72</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[75 Persian recipes made simple: many requiring only one pot and less than an hour to cook while keeping the authentic flavors of Iran. Includes many vegan and vegetarian options. In&#160;Joon,&#160;master chef&#160;Najmieh Batmanglij&#160;distills one of the world&#8217;s oldest and most influential cuisines to capture its unique flavors in recipes adapted to suit our busy lives.... <div class="link-more"><a href="https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/joon-persian-cooking-made-simple/">Read More</a></div>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>75 Persian recipes made simple: many requiring only one pot and less than an hour to cook while keeping the authentic flavors of Iran. Includes many vegan and vegetarian options.</p><p>In&nbsp;<strong><em>Joon,</em></strong>&nbsp;master chef&nbsp;<strong>Najmieh Batmanglij</strong>&nbsp;distills one of the world&#8217;s oldest and most influential cuisines to capture its unique flavors in recipes adapted to suit our busy lives. Najmieh&#8217;s fans have been making meals from her&nbsp;<em>Food of Life</em>&nbsp;for more than 30 years. For&nbsp;<em>Joon</em>&nbsp;she has simplified 75&nbsp;of her favorite dishes and shows how, with the right ingredients and a few basic tools and techniques, authentic Persian food can easily be prepared at home.</p></blockquote>



<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link" href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1933823720/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=persiancookbook-20&amp;linkId=586b3bb8e21ef453cd028e584b522c93&amp;language=en_US">Buy Now on Amazon for <img src="https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=persiancookbook-20&l=alb&o=1&a=1933823720" width="1px" height="1px" alt="" style="position: fixed !important; bottom: -1px !important; right: -1px !important; border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /></a></div>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/joon-persian-cooking-made-simple/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">72</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Persiana: Recipes from the Middle East &#038; beyond</title>
		<link>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/persiana-recipes-from-the-middle-east-beyond/</link>
					<comments>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/persiana-recipes-from-the-middle-east-beyond/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[persiancookbook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 17:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Sabrina Ghayour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persian cookbook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/?p=104</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A FABULOUS COLLECTION OF RECIPES FROM ONE OF THE STRONGEST VOICES IN MIDDLE EASTERN FOOD TODAY A celebration of the food and flavors from the regions near the Southern and Eastern shores of the Mediterranean Sea, with over 100 recipes for modern and accessible Middle Eastern dishes, including Lamb &#38; Sour Cherry Meatballs; Chicken, Preserved... <div class="link-more"><a href="https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/persiana-recipes-from-the-middle-east-beyond/">Read More</a></div>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>A FABULOUS COLLECTION OF RECIPES FROM ONE OF THE STRONGEST VOICES IN MIDDLE EASTERN FOOD TODAY<br><br>A celebration of the food and flavors from the regions near the Southern and Eastern shores of the Mediterranean Sea, with over 100 recipes for modern and accessible Middle Eastern dishes, including Lamb &amp; Sour Cherry Meatballs; Chicken, Preserved Lemon &amp; Olive Tagine; Blood Orange &amp; Radicchio Salad; Persian Flatbread; and Spiced Carrot, Pistachio &amp; Coconut Cake with Rosewater Cream.</p></blockquote>



<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link" href="https://amzn.to/2BTc7rB">Buy Now on Amazon for <img src="https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=persiancookbook-20&l=alb&o=1&a=1566569958" width="1px" height="1px" alt="" style="position: fixed !important; bottom: -1px !important; right: -1px !important; border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /></a></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/persiana-recipes-from-the-middle-east-beyond/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">104</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
