<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Najmieh Batmanglij &#8211; Persian Cookbook</title>
	<atom:link href="https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/author/persian-cookbook/najmieh-batmanglij/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com</link>
	<description>A collection of Persian cookbooks</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 23:02:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">197439166</site>	<item>
		<title>Cooking in Iran: Regional Recipes and Kitchen Secrets</title>
		<link>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/cooking-in-iran-regional-recipes-and-kitchen-secrets/</link>
					<comments>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/cooking-in-iran-regional-recipes-and-kitchen-secrets/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[persiancookbook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 23:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Najmieh Batmanglij]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/?p=210</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After five years of overcoming obstacles, meticulous planning, and ten thousand miles of traveling the length and breadth of Iran cooking with local cooks, visiting workshops, and developing recipes Najmieh&#8217;s dream has been realized with the creation of Cooking in Iran: Regional Recipes and Kitchen Secrets. This book is a distillation of those past five years. It... <div class="link-more"><a href="https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/cooking-in-iran-regional-recipes-and-kitchen-secrets/">Read More</a></div>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>After five years of overcoming obstacles, meticulous planning, and ten thousand miles of traveling the length and breadth of Iran cooking with local cooks, visiting workshops, and developing recipes Najmieh&#8217;s dream has been realized with the creation of <em>Cooking in Iran: Regional Recipes and Kitchen Secrets.</em> This book is a distillation of those past five years. It is an authoritative exploration of a cuisine whose cultural roots are among the deepest of any in the world.<br>Najmieh takes us with her on an extraordinary culinary journey: from the daily fish market in Bushehr, on the Persian Gulf, where she and her host buy and cook a 14-pound grouper in a tamarind, cilantro, and garlic sauce, to the heart of historical Isfahan, in central Iran, where she prepares lamb necks in a yogurt, saffron, and candied orange peel sauce topped with caramelized barberries. Traveling north to the Caspian Sea, she introduces us to the authentic Gilaki version of slow-cooked duck in a pomegranate and walnut sauce, served over smoked rice; and the unique flavors of a duck-egg omelet with smoked eggplant and baby garlic. Lingering in the north, in tribal Kurdistan, she treats us to lamb-and-bulgur meatballs filled with caramelized onions and raisins in a saffron sauce. Dropping south, to Bandar Abbas on the coast, she teases our palate with rice cooked in date juice and served with spicy fish, while in Baluchistan she cooks spiced goat in a pit overnight and celebrates the age-old method of making bread in hot ashes.<br>At every village and off-the-beaten-track community, Najmieh unearths traditional recipes and makes surprising new discoveries, giving us a glimpse along the way of the places where many of the ingredients for the recipes are grown. She treks through the fields and orchards of Iran, showing us saffron being picked in Khorasan and pomegranates in Yazd, dates harvested by the Persian Gulf, pistachios in Kerman, and tea and rice by the Caspian.<br>With more than 250 recipes and 400 photographs, <em>Cooking in Iran </em>is packed with inspiring ideas and practical tips everything you’ll need for recreating these glorious dishes so that you can embark on a culinary journey of your own.</p></blockquote>



<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Cooking-Iran-Regional-Recipes-Kitchen/dp/193382395X/ref=as_li_ss_tl?_encoding=UTF8&amp;psc=1&amp;refRID=TCN73SZXTVBX9DQWD67F&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=persiancookbook-20&amp;linkId=6b4b91946a00946c180c15749ffa24bd&amp;language=en_US">Buy Now on Amazon for <img src="https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=persiancookbook-20&l=alb&o=1&a=193382395X" width="1px" height="1px" alt="" style="position: fixed !important; bottom: -1px !important; right: -1px !important; border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /></a></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/cooking-in-iran-regional-recipes-and-kitchen-secrets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">210</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joon: Persian Cooking Made Simple</title>
		<link>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/joon-persian-cooking-made-simple/</link>
					<comments>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/joon-persian-cooking-made-simple/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[persiancookbook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 16:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Najmieh Batmanglij]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persian cookbook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/?p=72</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[75 Persian recipes made simple: many requiring only one pot and less than an hour to cook while keeping the authentic flavors of Iran. Includes many vegan and vegetarian options. In&#160;Joon,&#160;master chef&#160;Najmieh Batmanglij&#160;distills one of the world&#8217;s oldest and most influential cuisines to capture its unique flavors in recipes adapted to suit our busy lives.... <div class="link-more"><a href="https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/joon-persian-cooking-made-simple/">Read More</a></div>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>75 Persian recipes made simple: many requiring only one pot and less than an hour to cook while keeping the authentic flavors of Iran. Includes many vegan and vegetarian options.</p><p>In&nbsp;<strong><em>Joon,</em></strong>&nbsp;master chef&nbsp;<strong>Najmieh Batmanglij</strong>&nbsp;distills one of the world&#8217;s oldest and most influential cuisines to capture its unique flavors in recipes adapted to suit our busy lives. Najmieh&#8217;s fans have been making meals from her&nbsp;<em>Food of Life</em>&nbsp;for more than 30 years. For&nbsp;<em>Joon</em>&nbsp;she has simplified 75&nbsp;of her favorite dishes and shows how, with the right ingredients and a few basic tools and techniques, authentic Persian food can easily be prepared at home.</p></blockquote>



<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link" href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1933823720/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=persiancookbook-20&amp;linkId=586b3bb8e21ef453cd028e584b522c93&amp;language=en_US">Buy Now on Amazon for <img src="https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=persiancookbook-20&l=alb&o=1&a=1933823720" width="1px" height="1px" alt="" style="position: fixed !important; bottom: -1px !important; right: -1px !important; border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /></a></div>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/joon-persian-cooking-made-simple/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">72</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Food of Life: Ancient Persian and Modern Iranian Cooking and Ceremonies</title>
		<link>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/food-of-life-ancient-persian-and-modern-iranian-cooking-and-ceremonies/</link>
					<comments>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/food-of-life-ancient-persian-and-modern-iranian-cooking-and-ceremonies/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[persiancookbook]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 16:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Najmieh Batmanglij]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food-of-life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foodoflife]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persian cookbook]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/?p=62</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Completely redesigned for today&#8217;s generation of cooks and food enthusiasts,&#160;the 25th Anniversary Edition of Food of Life: Ancient Persian and Modern Iranian Cooking and Ceremonies&#160;by Najmieh Batmanglij&#160;provides a treasure trove of recipes, along with an immersive cultural experience for those seeking to understand this ancient and timeless cuisine. This edition is a more user-friendly edition... <div class="link-more"><a href="https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/food-of-life-ancient-persian-and-modern-iranian-cooking-and-ceremonies/">Read More</a></div>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><strong>Completely redesigned for today&#8217;s generation of cooks and food enthusiasts,<em>&nbsp;the 25th Anniversary Edition of Food of Life: Ancient Persian and Modern Iranian Cooking and Ceremonies</em>&nbsp;by Najmieh Batmanglij&nbsp;</strong>provides a treasure trove of recipes, along with an immersive cultural experience for those seeking to understand this ancient and timeless cuisine. This edition is a more user-friendly edition of the award-winning and critically acclaimed cookbook series which began in 1986.&nbsp;<em>Food of Life&nbsp;</em>provides 330 classical and regional Iranian recipes as well as an introduction to Persian art, history, and culture. The book&#8217;s hundreds of full color photographs are intertwined with descriptions of ancient and modern Persian ceremonies, poetry, folktales, travelogue excerpts and anecdotes. The 2011 Edition of&nbsp;<em>Food of Life</em>&nbsp;is a labor of love. The book began in exile after the Iranian Revolution of 1979 as a love letter to Batmanglij&#8217;s children. Today, as accomplished adults in their own fields, her two sons, Zal and Rostam, encouraged her to redesign the book for their generation.&nbsp;<strong><em>Food of Life</em>&nbsp;propels Persian cooking into the 21st Century,&nbsp;</strong>even as it honors venerable traditions and centuries of artistic expression. It is the result of 30 years of collecting, testing and adapting authentic and traditional Persian recipes for the American kitchen. Most of its ingredients are readily available throughout the U.S. enabling anyone from a master chef to a novice to reproduce the refined tastes, textures, and beauty of Persian cuisine. Food-related pieces from such classics as the 10th century&nbsp;<em>Book of Kings,</em>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<em>1,001 Nights</em>&nbsp;to the miniatures of Mir Mosavvar and Aq Mirak, from the poetry of Omar Khayyam and Sohrab Sepehri to the humor of Mulla Nasruddin are all included. Each recipe is presented with steps that are logical and easy to follow. Readers learn how to simply yet deliciously cook rice, the jewel of Persian cooking, which, when combined with a little meat, fowl, or fish, vegetables, fruits, and herbs, provides the perfect balanced diet.<br></p></blockquote>



<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link" href="https://www.amazon.com/Food-Life-Ancient-Persian-Ceremonies/dp/193382347X/ref=as_li_ss_tl?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1546274047&amp;sr=1-3&amp;keywords=persian+cookbooks&amp;linkCode=ll1&amp;tag=persiancookbook-20&amp;linkId=06cf1c0cdb5e50641c8af969d1d0f128&amp;language=en_US">Buy Now on Amazon for <img src="https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=persiancookbook-20&l=alb&o=1&a=193382347X" width="1px" height="1px" alt="" style="position: fixed !important; bottom: -1px !important; right: -1px !important; border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /></a></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://persiancookbook-clone.mystagingwebsite.com/food-of-life-ancient-persian-and-modern-iranian-cooking-and-ceremonies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">62</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
